So it's 2006.
إنه العام 2006،
My friend Harold Ford calls me.
اتصل بي صديقي هارولد فورد،
He's running for U.S. Senate in Tennessee,
وهو مرشح لانتخابات مجلس الشيوخ الأمريكي بولاية تينسي،
and he says, "Mellody, I desperately need some national press. Do you have any ideas?"
وقال لي: "ميلودي، أنا في أمس الحاجة لبعض التغطية الإعلامية، هل لديك أية اقتراحات؟"
So I had an idea. I called a friend
فاتصلت بصديقتي
who was in New York
التي تعمل بنيويورك
at one of the most successful media companies in the world,
بواحدة من أكثر شركات الإعلام نجاحًا في العالم،
and she said, "Why don't we host
وقالت: " لماذا لا نقيم
an editorial board lunch for Harold?
عشاء لهيئة التحرير على شرف هارولد؟
You come with him."
وبإمكانك الحضور معه."
Harold and I arrive in New York.
وصلنا أنا وهارولد إلى نيويورك.
We are in our best suits.
وكنا نرتدي أبهى حللنا
We look like shiny new pennies.
ونشع كالنجوم.
And we get to the receptionist, and we say,
توجهنا لموظفة الاستقبال وقلنا لها
"We're here for the lunch."
"نحن هنا من أجل العشاء"
She motions for us to follow her.
فأشارت لنا لنتبعها.
We walk through a series of corridors,
مشينا عبر عدد من الممرات،
and all of a sudden we find ourselves
وللمفاجأة وجدنا أنفسنا
in a stark room,
في غرفة لوحدنا،
at which point she looks at us and she says,
عندها نظرت إلينا وقالت
"Where are your uniforms?"
"أين لباسكم الموحد؟"
Just as this happens,
وفي أثناء حدوث ذلك،
my friend rushes in.
دخلت صديقتي إلى الغرفة.
The blood drains from her face.
فشحب وجهها خجلًا.
There are literally no words, right?
لا تسعفنا الكلمات لوصف هذا الموقف, اليس كذلك؟
And I look at her, and I say,
نظرت إلى صديقتي وقلت،
"Now, don't you think we need
" ألا تعتقدين الآن أننا بحاجة إلى أكثر من
Now Harold and I --
ومازلنا أنا وهارولد -
(Applause) —
(تصفيق) -
we still laugh about that story,
نضحك على هذا الموقف.
and in many ways, the moment caught me off guard,
وبشتى السبل، لم أكن لأتخيل حصول مثل هذا الموقف.
but deep, deep down inside,
ولكن في دواخل أعماقي،
I actually wasn't surprised.
فإنه لم يفاجئني.
And I wasn't surprised because of something
لم أتفاجأ بسبب
my mother taught me about 30 years before.
ما علمتني أمي إياه قبل 30 عام.
You see, my mother was ruthlessly realistic.
أمي كانت واقعية جدًا.
I remember one day coming home from a birthday party
أتذكر مرة عدت للمنزل من حفلة عيد ميلاد
where I was the only black kid invited,
وكنت الطفلة السوداء الوحيدة المدعوة
and instead of asking me the normal motherly questions
وبدل أن تسألني الأسئلة المعتادة التي تسألها الأمهات
like, "Did you have fun?" or "How was the cake?"
مثل:" هل استمتعت؟" أو "كيف كانت الكعكة؟"
my mother looked at me and she said,
نظرت إلي أمي وقالت:
"How did they treat you?"
"كيف عاملوكِ؟"
I was seven. I did not understand.
كُنت في السابعة من عمري ولم أفهم حينها ما قصدته أمي.
I mean, why would anyone treat me differently?
أقصد، لم قد يعاملوني بطريقة مختلفة؟
But she knew.
ولكن أمي كانت تعرف.
And she looked me right in the eye and she said,
ونظرت إلي مباشرة وقالت:
"They will not always treat you well."
"لن يعاملوك دائما بطريقة جيدة."
Now, race is one of those topics in America
العنصرية هي أحد تلك المواضيع في أمريكا
that makes people extraordinarily uncomfortable.
التي تجعل الناس غير مرتاحين للغاية.
You bring it up at a dinner party
حاول ذكرها بحفلات العشاء
or in a workplace environment,
أو في مكان العمل،
it is literally the conversational equivalent
إنها المرادف الحواري
of touching the third rail.
لملامسة الخطر.
There is shock,
هناك صدمة،
followed by a long silence.
تتبعها فترة سكوت طويلة.
And even coming here today,
وحتى اليوم بمجيئي هنا.
I told some friends and colleagues
أخبرت بعض أصدقائي ورفاقي
that I planned to talk about race,
أني أنوي التحدث عن العرق.
and they warned me, they told me, don't do it,
فحذروني ألا أفعل ذلك،
that there'd be huge risks
لما في ذلك من مخاطر،
in me talking about this topic,
بالنسبة لي حين أتطرق لذلك الموضوع
that people might think I'm a militant black woman
بأن يصنفني الجمهور كامرأة سوداء متشددة
and I would ruin my career.
مما قد يؤدي إلى تدمير حياتي المهنية.
And I have to tell you,
وللحقيقة علي أن أصارحكم،
I actually for a moment was a bit afraid.
لقد أخافني هذا الكلام لوهلة.
Then I realized,
ولكن عندها استوعبت،
the first step to solving any problem
بأن أول مرحلة بحل أي مشكلة
is to not hide from it,
هي عدم تجنبها.
and the first step to any form of action
وأن أول خطوة لأي شكل من أشكال العمل
is awareness.
هو الوعي.
And so I decided to actually talk about race.
ولهذا قررت أن أتحدث فعليًا عن العنصرية.
And I decided that if I came here and shared with you
وبالتالي قررت أن أحضر إلى هنا وأشارككم
some of my experiences,
جزءً من تجاربي.
that maybe we could all be a little less anxious
مما قد يجعلنا كلنا أقل قلقًا
and a little more bold
وأكثر جرأة
in our conversations about race.
في حديثنا عن العنصرية.
Now I know there are people out there who will say
أدرك أن هنالك من يدعي
that the election of Barack Obama meant
أن انتخاب براك أوباما لرئاسة الولايات المتحدة
that it was the end of racial discrimination
تشير إلى نهاية التمييز العنصري للأبد،
But I work in the investment business,
لكني أعمل بمجال الاستثمارات،
and we have a saying:
ونقول دائمًا:
The numbers do not lie.
الأرقام لا تكذب.
And here, there are significant,
وهنالك، بشكل محسوس،
quantifiable racial disparities
الفوارق العرقية القابلة للقياس الكمي
that cannot be ignored,
بشكل لا يمكن تجاهله:
in household wealth, household income,
في ثروات الأسر، في الدّخل،
job opportunities, healthcare.
في فرص العمل وفي الرعاية الصحية.
One example from corporate America:
مثال من الشركات الأمريكية:
Even though white men
بالرغم من أن الرجال البيض
make up just 30 percent of the U.S. population,
يشكلون فقط 30% من سكان الولايات المتحدة،
they hold 70 percent of all corporate board seats.
فإنهم يشغلون 70% من المقاعد في مجالس الشركات.
Of the Fortune 250,
من أقوى 250 شركة حسب مجلة فورتشن،
there are only seven CEOs that are minorities,
هنالك فقط 7 من كبار المديرين التنفيذيين ممن ينتمون للأقليات،
and of the thousands of publicly traded companies today, thousands,
ومن بين آلاف الشركات التي تباع علانية، آلاف،
only two are chaired by black women,
فقط اثنتين منهما تترأسهما امراة سوداء،
and you're looking at one of them,
والواقفه أمامكم الآن إحداهما،
the same one who, not too long ago,
وهي نفسها من أعتبرت من وقت ليس ببعيد،
was nearly mistaken for kitchen help.
عن طريق الخطأ، عاملة مطبخ.
So that is a fact.
إذًا نحن نتكلم عن حقائق.
Now I have this thought experiment
لدي تمرين ذهني
that I play with myself, when I say,
أتسلى بهـ عندما أقول،
imagine if I walked you into a room
تخيلوا لو أنني دخلت إلى قاعة
and it was of a major corporation, like ExxonMobil,
لإحدى الشركات الكبرى، مثل إكسون موبيل،
and every single person around the boardroom were black,
وكل شخص بغرفة الإدارة كان أسودًا،
you would think that were weird.
كنت لأظن أن هذا أمر غريب.
But if I walked you into a Fortune 500 company,
ولكن إذا دخلت لشركة من شركات مجلة فورتشن 500،
and everyone around the table is a white male,
وكل الحاضرين بالغرف رجال بيض،
when will it be that we think that's weird too?
متى كنا سنفكر بأن هذا الأمر غريب كذلك؟
And I know how we got here.
وأنا أعرف كيف وصلنا لهذا الوضع.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
I know how we got here.
أعرف كيف وصلنا إلى هذا الوضع.
You know, there was institutionalized,
كما تعرفون، كان هناك طابع مؤسسي،
at one time legalized, discrimination in our country.
وحتى قانوني بفترة معينة للتمييز بدولتنا.
There's no question about it.
هذه حقيقة لا تقبل الجدل.
But still, as I grapple with this issue,
مع هذا كل ما أتخبط أكثر بهذا بالموضوع،
my mother's question hangs in the air for me:
أتذكر مجددًا سؤال أمي يلوح لي في الأفق:
How did they treat you?
"كيف عاملوكِ؟"
Now, I do not raise this issue to complain
أنا لا أقوم بطرح هذه الاسئلة من باب التذمر
or in any way to elicit any kind of sympathy.
أو لإثارة أي نوع من التعاطف،
I have succeeded in my life
لقد نجحت في حياتي
beyond my wildest expectations,
بما يفوق كل توقعاتي،
and I have been treated well by people of all races
وقد عُملت بطريقة جيدة، من شتى الأعراق،
more often than I have not.
أكثر من العكس.
I tell the uniform story because it happened.
سردت قصة الزي الموحد لأنها حدثت بالفعل.
I cite those statistics around corporate board diversity
وذكرت المعطيات عن التنوّع العرقي في إداراة الشركات
because they are real,
لأنها حقيقية،
and I stand here today
وأنا أقف هنا اليوم
talking about this issue of racial discrimination
أتحدث عن معضلة التفرقة العنصرية
because I believe it threatens to rob
أيمانًا مني بأنها تهدد بأن تحرم
another generation of all the opportunities
جيلًا آخر من جميع الفرص
that all of us want for all of our children,
التي نتمناها جميعًأ لأبنائنا،
no matter what their color
مهما كان لون بشرتهم
or where they come from.
أو مهما كان أصلهم.
And I think it also threatens to hold back businesses.
كما أظن أنها تهدد بإعاقة الأعمال.
You see, researchers have coined this term
كما تعرفون، قام بعض الباحثين بصياغة مصطلح
"color blindness"
"عمى الألوان"
to describe a learned behavior where we pretend
لوصف طريقة تصرف يدعي متبعها
that we don't notice race.
بأنه يتصرف متجاهلًا الأنتماء العرقي.
If you happen to be surrounded by a bunch of people
فإن حدث وكنت محاطًا بمجموعة من الناس
who look like you, that's purely accidental.
الذين يشبهكونك، فإن هذا من باب الصدفة لا غير.
Now, color blindness, in my view,
"عمى الألوان" بنظري
doesn't mean that there's no racial discrimination,
لا يعني عدم وجود تمييز عنصري،
and there's fairness.
والأمور تسير بطريقة عادلة ومنصفة.
It doesn't mean that at all. It doesn't ensure it.
ليس هذا المقصود. كما أنه لا يكفل هذه النتيجة.
In my view, color blindness is very dangerous
بنظري، سياسة "عمى الألوان" خطيرة جدًا
because it means we're ignoring the problem.
لأنها تعني أننا نقوم بتجاهل المشكلة.
There was a corporate study that said that,
هنالك دراسة تثبت أنه
instead of avoiding race,
بدلًا من تفادي العرق،
the really smart corporations actually deal with it head on.
الشركات الذكية حقًا بالواقع تقوم بمواجهته.
They actually recognize that embracing diversity
حيث أنها تدرك أن احتضان التنوع
means recognizing all races,
يعني الاعتراف بكل الأعراق،
including the majority one.
بما في ذلك العرق الذي تنتمي له الأغلبية.
But I'll be the first one to tell you,
سأكون أول من يخبركم
this subject matter can be hard,
أن هذا ليس بالأمر السهل،
awkward, uncomfortable -- but that's kind of the point.
هو محرج وغير مريح، لكن هذا جزء من الموضوع.
In the spirit of debunking racial stereotypes,
بروح فضح الأفكار المسبقة العرقية،
the one that black people don't like to swim,
مثلًا أن السود لا يحبون السباحة،
I'm going to tell you how much I love to swim.
سأخبركم مدى حبي للسباحة.
I love to swim so much
أحب السباحة لدرجة أنني
that as an adult, I swim with a coach.
كشخص راشد، أسبح برفقة مدرب شخصي.
And one day my coach had me do a drill
وفي أحد الأيام طلب مني المدرب
where I had to swim to one end of a 25-meter pool
أن أقطع سباحة بركة بطول 25م
without taking a breath.
دون أن آخد نفسًا.
And every single time I failed,
وفي كل مرة فشلت بها،
I had to start over.
كان علي أن أعيد المحاولة.
And I failed a lot.
وفشلت عدة مرات.
By the end, I got it, but when I got out of the pool,
بالنهاية، بعد نجاحي خرجت من البركة
I was exasperated and tired and annoyed,
غاضبة ومتعبة ومنزعجة،
and I said, "Why are we doing breath-holding exercises?"
وسألت المدرب: "لماذا نقوم بتمارين حبس النفس؟"
And my coach looked me at me, and he said, "Mellody,
فنظر الي وأجاب: "ميلودي،
that was not a breath-holding exercise.
لم يكن هذا تمرين بحبس النفس.
That drill was to make you comfortable
لقد كان هذا تمرينًا لجعلك مرتاحة
being uncomfortable,
بأن تكوني بوضعية غير مريحة،
because that's how most of us spend our days."
لأن غالبيتنا تقضي أغلب أيامها بوضعية كهذة"
If we can learn to deal with our discomfort,
فإن تعلمنا التعامل مع حالات عدم الراحة،
and just relax into it,
وتعودنا أن نرتاح بها،
we'll have a better life.
سنعيش حياةً أفضل.
So I think it's time for us to be comfortable
لهذا أظن أنه قد حان الآوان لنشعر بالراحة
with the uncomfortable conversation about race:
حيال المحادثة غير المريحة عن العرق.
black, white, Asian, Hispanic,
أسود، أبيض، آسيوي، إسباني الأصل،
male, female, all of us,
ذكر، أنثى، جميعنا،
if we truly believe in equal rights
إن كنا نؤمن بالمساواة بالحقوق
and equal opportunity in America,
والمساواة بالفرص في الولايات المتحدة،
I think we have to have real conversations
أظن أن علينا أن نتحدث بصراحة
about this issue.
عن هذا الموضوع.
We cannot afford to be color blind.
لا مجال أمامنا لأن ننتهج سياسة "عمى الألوان"
We have to be color brave.
علينا أن نكون شجاعين حيال الألوان.
We have to be willing, as teachers and parents
علينا أن نرغب، كمربين وكوالدين
and entrepreneurs and scientists,
وكرجال أعمال وعلماء،
we have to be willing to have
علينا جميعًا أن نرغب في التطرق
proactive conversations about race
لموضوع العرق بطريقة استباقية
with honesty and understanding and courage,
بصراحة وبفهم وبشجاعة،
not because it's the right thing to do,
ليس لأن هذا هو الأمر الصحيح لنفعله،
but because it's the smart thing to do,
ولكنه الأمر الأذكى.
because our businesses and our products
لأن أعمالنا ومنتجاتنا
and our science, our research,
وعلمنا وأبحاثنا،
all of that will be better with greater diversity.
كلها ستكون أفضل مع زيادة التنوعية.
Now, my favorite example of color bravery
المثال المفضل على " شجاعة الألوان"
is a guy named John Skipper.
شخص إسمه جون سكيبر.
He runs ESPN.
هو يدير شبكة "إسبين" التلفزيونية
He's a North Carolina native,
هو بالأصل من كارولينا الشمالية،
quintessential Southern gentleman, white.
رجل مثالي من الجنوب، أبيض.
He joined ESPN, which already had a culture
انضم إلى "إسبين" التي كانت قد تمييزت بثقافة
of inclusion and diversity, but he took it up a notch.
شمولية وتنوعية ولكنه قام بخطى إضافية بهذا المجال.
He demanded that every open position
لقد أمر بأن تقدم له لائحة متنوعة
have a diverse slate of candidates.
من المرشحين لكل وظيفة شاغرة.
Now he says the senior people
قال "في البداية لم يرق الأمر لكبار الموظفين"
and they would come to him and say,
فأتوا إليه وسألوه
"Do you want me to hire the minority,
"أتريدنا أن نختار مرشحًا من أقلية عرقية،
And Skipper says his answers were always the same:
ويقول سكيبر أن أجوبته كانت دائمًا:
"Yes."
"نعم".
And by saying yes to diversity,
وبالموافقة على التنوع،
I honestly believe that ESPN
أنا أعتقد أن "إسبين" تعتبر
is the most valuable cable franchise in the world.
أكثر شركات التلفاز قيمة في العالم.
I think that's a part of the secret sauce.
أظن أن هذا جزء من سر نجاحها.
Now I can tell you, in my own industry,
أستطيع إخباركم، من تجربتي في مجالي،
at Ariel Investments, we actually view our diversity
بشركة آريل الاستثمارية نحن نعتبر تنوعنا،
as a competitive advantage,
أفضلية تنافسية.
and that advantage can extend way beyond business.
ويمكن الاستفادة من هذه الأفضلية ليس فقط بأعمالنا.
There's a guy named Scott Page at the University of Michigan.
هنالك شخص يدعى سكوت بيج من جامعة مشيغين
He is the first person to develop
وهو أول من طوّر
a mathematical calculation for diversity.
نموذجا رياضيا لحساب التنوعية.
He says, if you're trying to solve a really hard problem,
برأيه، إن كنت تبحث عن حل لمشكلة صعبة،
really hard,
صعبة جدًا،
that you should have a diverse group of people,
فيجب أن تكون لديك مجموعة متنوعة من الناس،
including those with diverse intellects.
بما في ذلك أشخاصا ذوي قدرات عقلية متنوعة.
The example that he gives is the smallpox epidemic.
المثال الذي يعطيه هو وباء الجدري.
When it was ravaging Europe,
في فترة اجتياحه لأوروبا
they brought together all these scientists,
قاموا بتجميع مجموعة من العلماء
and they were stumped.
ولكنهم كانوا بحيرة من أمرهم.
And the beginnings of the cure to the disease
بداية العلاج للوباء
came from the most unlikely source,
أتت من أقل المصادر توقعًا،
a dairy farmer who noticed that the milkmaids
مربي مواشٍ لاحظ أن العاملات بالحلب
were not getting smallpox.
لا تمرضن بالجدري.
And the smallpox vaccination is bovine-based
والتطعيم ضد الجدري يشتمل على مواد من الأبقار
because of that dairy farmer.
بفضل مربي المواشي ذاك.
Now I'm sure you're sitting here and you're saying,
أنا متأكدة أنكم تجلسون هنا الآن وتفكرون
I don't run a cable company,
أنكم لا تديرون شركة تلفزيونية،
I don't run an investment firm,
ولا شركة استثمار،
I am not a dairy farmer.
ولستم بمربي مواشي.
What can I do?
فماذا باستطاعتكم أن تفعلوا؟
And I'm telling you, you can be color brave.
ولكني أخبركم، باستطاعكتم أن تكونوا شجاعين حيال الألوان.
If you're part of a hiring process
إن كنتم جزءً من سيرورة التوظيف،
or an admissions process,
أو عملية القبول،
you can be color brave.
بإمكانكم أن تكونوا شجاعين حيال الألوان،
If you are trying to solve a really hard problem,
إن كنتم تحاولون حل مشكلة صعبة جدًا،
you can speak up and be color brave.
بأمكانكم أن تسمعوا صوتكم وأن تكونوا شجاعين حيال الألوان،
Now I know people will say,
أعرف أن البعض قد يقول،
but that doesn't add up to a lot,
لكن هذا لا يضيف الكثير،
but I'm actually asking you to do something really simple:
ولكني عمليًا أسالكم أن تقوموا بأمر جد بسيط:
observe your environment,
تأملوا في محيطكم،
at work, at school, at home.
بالعمل، بالمدرسة، وبالمنزل.
I'm asking you to look at the people around you
أطلب منكم أن تنظروا إلى الناس المحيطين بكم،
purposefully and intentionally.
بشكل مقصود وهادف.
Invite people into your life
ادعو إلى حياتكم
who don't look like you, don't think like you,
الناس اللذين لا يشبهونكم منظرًا أو فكرًا
don't act like you,
أو يتصرفون مثلكم،
don't come from where you come from,
أو يأتون من مكان غير الذي تأتون منه،
and you might find that they will challenge your assumptions
وربما قد تجدوا أنهم يتحدون افتراضاتكم
and make you grow as a person.
ويجعلونكم تنمون كأشخاص.
You might get powerful new insights
قد تكتشفون رؤى جديدة وقوية
from these individuals,
من هؤلاء الأشخاص،
or, like my husband, who happens to be white,
أو، مثل زوجي، الذي يحدث أنه أبيض اللون
you might learn that black people,
ربما قد تعلم أن السود،
men, women, children,
الرجال والنساء والأطفال،
we use body lotion every single day.
نستخدم غسول الجسم كل يوم.
Now, I also think that this is very important
الآن، وأعتقد أيضا أن هذا مهم جدا
so that the next generation really understands
ذلك أن الجيل القادم يفهم حقا
that this progress will help them,
أن هذا التقدم سوف يساعدهم،
because they're expecting us to be great role models.
لأنهم يتوقعون منا أن تكون قدوة عظيمة.
Now, I told you, my mother,
الآن، قلت لكم، بأن أمي،
she was ruthlessly realistic.
كانت واقعية جدًا.
She was an unbelievable role model.
كانت قدوة رائعة جدًا.
She was the kind of person
وكانت من النوعية
who got to be the way she was
التي أصبحت بتلك الشخصية
because she was a single mom
لأنها كانت أم عازبة
with six kids in Chicago.
مع ستة أطفال في شيكاغو.
She was in the real estate business,
وكانت تعمل في مجال العقار،
where she worked extraordinarily hard
حيث عملت بجد للغاية
but oftentimes had a hard time making ends meet.
في كثير من الأحيان تجد صعوبة في تلبية الأحتياجات.
And that meant sometimes we got
وهذا يعني في بعض الأحيان أن يكون
our phone disconnected,
هاتفنا مفصولا،
or our lights turned off,
أو الكهرباء مقطوعة،
or we got evicted.
أو يتم إخلاؤنا.
When we got evicted, sometimes we lived
عندما يتم إخلاؤنا، أحيانا كنا نعيش
in these small apartments that she owned,
في شقق صغيرة كانت تملكها،
sometimes in only one or two rooms,
أحيانا في غرفة واحد أو اثنتين فقط،
because they weren't completed,
لأنها لم تكتمل،
and we would heat our bathwater on hot plates.
وكنا نسخن مياه الاستحمام على الموقد.
But she never gave up hope, ever,
لكنها لم تفقد الأمل، مطلقًا،
and she never allowed us to give up hope either.
ولم تكن تسمح لنا أيضًا بأن نفقد الأمل.
This brutal pragmatism that she had,
هذه البراغماتية الوحشية التي كانت عليها،
I mean, I was four and she told me,
أعني، كنت في سن الرابعة وقالت لي،
"Mommy is Santa." (Laughter)
"أمي هي سانتا". (ضحك)
She was this brutal pragmatism.
وكانت هذه البراغماتية وحشية.
She taught me so many lessons,
علمتني الكثير من الدروس،
but the most important lesson
لكن الدرس الأهم
was that every single day she told me,
كانت تقول لي يوميًا،
"Mellody, you can be anything."
"ميلودي، يمكنك أن تكوني ما تطمحين له."
And because of those words,
وبسبب هذه الكلمات،
I would wake up at the crack of dawn,
أتستيقظ مع بزوغ الفجر،
I would love school more than anything,
أحببت المدرسة أكثر من أي شيء
and because of those words, when I was on a bus
وبسبب هذه الكلمات، عندما كنت على متن حافلة
going to school, I dreamed the biggest dreams.
ذاهبة للمدرسة، كنت أحلم بأحلام كبيرة.
And it's because of those words that I stand here right now
وبسبب تلك الكلمات أنا أقف هنا
full of passion,
مليئة بالعاطفة،
asking you to be brave for the kids
أطلب منكم أن تكونوا شجعان من أجل الأطفال
who are dreaming those dreams today.
الذين يحلمون بتلك الأحلام اليوم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
You see, I want them to look at a CEO on television
أريد لهم أن ينظروا إلى رئيس تنفيذي على التلفاز
and say, "I can be like her,"
ويقولو: "أستطيع أن أكون مثله"
or, "He looks like me."
أو، "إنه يشبهني".
And I want them to know
وأريد لهم أن يعرفوا
that anything is possible,
أن كل شيء ممكن،
that they can achieve the highest level
يمكن أن يصلوا لأعلى المستويات
that they ever imagined,
التي يتخيلونها من أي وقت مضى،
that they will be welcome in any corporate boardroom,
وأنهم موضع ترحيب في أي مجالس إدارة الشركات،
or they can lead any company.
أو بإمكانهم أن يديروا أي شركة.
You see this idea of being the land
لفكرة كون أمريكا أرض
of the free and the home of the brave,
الأحرار وموطن الشجعان،
it's woven into the fabric of America.
قد نُسجت في بِنية أمريكا.
America, when we have a challenge,
عندما تواجه أمريكا التحدي،
we take it head on, we don't shrink away from it.
نواجهه مباشرة، ولا نحاول التملص منه
We take a stand. We show courage.
نتخذ موفقا. ونُظهر شجاعة.
So right now, what I'm asking you to do,
حتى الآن، ما أطلبه منكم،
I'm asking you to show courage.
أنا أطلب منكم أن تُظهروا الشجاعة.
I'm asking you to be bold.
أنا أطلب منكم أن تكونوا جريئين.
As business leaders, I'm asking you
كرائدة أعمال، أطلب منكم
not to leave anything on the table.
عدم ترك أي شيء على الطاولة.
As citizens, I'm asking you not to leave any child behind.
كمواطنة، أطلب منكم عدم ترك أي طفل وراءكم.
I'm asking you not to be color blind,
أنا أطلب منكم أن لا تكونوا مصابين بعمى الألوان،
but to be color brave,
بل أن تكونوا شجاعين حيال الألوان،
so that every child knows that their future matters
بحيث يعرف كل طفل أن المستقبل مهم
and their dreams are possible.
وأن أحلامه ممكنة.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
Thank you. Thanks. Thanks. (Applause)
شكرًا جزيلا. شكرًا. (تصفيق)